<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cbse-science on BetterTexts</title><link>https://bettertexts.github.io/tags/cbse-science/</link><description>Recent content in cbse-science on BetterTexts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:53:07 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bettertexts.github.io/tags/cbse-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do organisms reproduce?</title><link>https://bettertexts.github.io/post/science/reproduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 13:53:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://bettertexts.github.io/post/science/reproduction/</guid><description>How do organisms reproduce? Introduction Reproduction is basically creating others of one's own kind. It's not required to maintain the life of an individual organism, but it is required to keep the species alive.
At the most basic level, reproduction involves the copying of one organism's DNA i.e DeoxyriboNucleic Acid, they are just some molecules that have instructions to build up an organism. The DNA molecules are embedded in structures called chromosomes which are present in the nucleus of the cell.</description></item><item><title>Our Environment</title><link>https://bettertexts.github.io/post/science/our-environment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 11:06:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://bettertexts.github.io/post/science/our-environment/</guid><description>1. Ecosystems An ecosystem is a complex system which consists of all the living organisms and the non-living constituents of an area.
These may include:
Biotic components, comprising living organisms Abiotic components, including physical factors like temperature rainfall wind soil 1.1 Examples of Ecosystems Take a pond for example. A variety of animals and plants (biotic components) can be found in and around a pond. These living beings are dependent on each other as well as the surrounding water, air and soil (abiotic components).</description></item></channel></rss>